<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<rss version="2.0">
 <channel>
  <title>Mistake Not: Posts tagged 'flipism'</title>
  <description>Mistake Not: Posts tagged 'flipism'</description>
  <link>http://pookleblinky.github.io/tags/flipism.html</link>
  <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 09:36:58 UT</lastBuildDate>
  <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 09:36:58 UT</pubDate>
  <ttl>1800</ttl>
  <item>
   <title>Lifescripts: Stochastic routines</title>
   <link>http://pookleblinky.github.io/2018/02/lifescripts-stochastic-routines.html?utm_source=flipism&amp;utm_medium=RSS</link>
   <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:http-pookleblinky-github-io:-2018-02-lifescripts-stochastic-routines-html</guid>
   <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 09:36:58 UT</pubDate>
   <author>Pookleblinky</author>
   <description>
&lt;p&gt;Since November I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a form of intermittent fasting I created based on coinflips, that I call coinfasting. Every morning flip a coin. Heads, you eat, tails you fast. The expected value of heads over 7 days is 3.5, so it&amp;rsquo;s identical in effect to a scheduled alternate day fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(As an aside: since August I&amp;rsquo;ve lost about 22kg, or about 24% of my bodyweight.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The introduction of randomness makes things interesting: you can&amp;rsquo;t just binge on heads days, because you may get a bunch in a row. And you can&amp;rsquo;t restrict too much on fast days, because you may get a bunch of fast days in a row. This makes it easier to dial in on the right amount of calories, and lets the meals be a bit less absurd than on a normal ADF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After doing this a while, I love it. It feels fun and sustainable, and is easily modifiable. When I hit maintenance, I can such as switch heads to TDEE+15%, tails to TDEE&amp;ndash;15% easily. The only actual daily habit that needs to be engrained is one cointoss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to embrace more flipism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each morning I do 20 minutes of cycling. On heads days I add another 30 minute afternoon cycling session. This gives a baseline of 140 minutes, which is the minimum recommended dose of cardio, and averages over time to another 105 minutes for a total of 245 minutes a week. Maximum: 350 minutes a week. This is a good amount of cardio, as the maximum effective dose of cardio is about 450 minutes a week &lt;a href="https://well.blogs.nytimes.com/2015/04/15/the-right-dose-of-exercise-for-a-longer-life/"&gt;The Right Dose of Exercise for a Longer Life&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s both calories and LISS out of the way, with one coinflip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then based my kettlebell on dice. After flipping the coin, roll 2d6 and multiply by a number to get the number of swings that day. I chose a multiplier of 10. On average, 70 swings a day, maximum 120. This is because any more swings right now would bite into my deficit too much. Later, I can toggle the amount based on the coinflip: heads 25, tails 10. This&amp;rsquo;d bring me to a maximum of 300 swings a day, and an average of 210.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;d been doing for a while. Some days I&amp;rsquo;d physically flip a coin and roll dice, other days I&amp;rsquo;d just ask my phone to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to automate this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a git repo called Lifescripts, and began making small racket programs to at first simply do what I&amp;rsquo;m already doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I can simultaneously flip and roll for the day with one command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The git repo is here: &lt;a href="https://github.com/pookleblinky/lifescripts"&gt;pookleblinky/lifescripts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then added a script to decide whether to engage in argument, a script to decide whether to cuss. One to decide the music of the day, one to decide which topic to boost for the day. A script to decide whether to refactor or write new code. One to assign a random small task like doing kettlebell swings or clean something.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>